<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>DIY on Xuanming Zhou</title>
    <link>https://xuanmingzhou.com/categories/diy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in DIY on Xuanming Zhou</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 23:40:34 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://xuanmingzhou.com/categories/diy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /> }}
    <item>
      <title>K&amp;N Apollo for my Cruze</title>
      <link>https://xuanmingzhou.com/blog/kn-apollo-for-my-cruze/</link>
      <image>https://xuanmingzhou.com/../../images/blog/apollo-cruze-00.jpg</image>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 23:40:34 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xuanmingzhou.com/blog/kn-apollo-for-my-cruze/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always loved cars—reading about them, watching builds online, admiring them on the streets—but until recently, I’d never actually worked on one myself. That all changed when a broken side mirror pushed me to get hands-on for the first time. What started as a simple fix turned into a deep dive into DIY car mods, and before I knew it, I was designing parts, printing adapters, and upgrading my intake system.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
     }}
    <item>
      <title>Making My Own Arcade Fightstick</title>
      <link>https://xuanmingzhou.com/blog/making-my-own-arcade-fightstick/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 19:40:34 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xuanmingzhou.com/blog/making-my-own-arcade-fightstick/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always been interested in fighting games. Since &lt;em&gt;Street Fighter II: World Warrior&lt;/em&gt; in my youth, to &lt;em&gt;Guilty Gear XX #Reload&lt;/em&gt;, to my current favorite, &lt;em&gt;Street Fighter V: Arcade Edition&lt;/em&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ve spent quite some money acquiring fightsticks for the authentic arcade experience (although the nostalgic factor is a little misplaced for me as I mostly played on consoles), but I recently got bitten by the DIY bug and started refurbishing old fightsticks to make them compatible with newer systems like the PS4. Then a voice in my head spoke to me: &amp;ldquo;Why not make one from scratch?&amp;rdquo; Another voice in my head said &amp;ldquo;That way lies madness.&amp;rdquo; I ignored the latter and got to work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>